Previously on The Guardian.
Talik Allen, six months ago, was an victim of a brutal assault.
Talik put the gun...
Your client has been informed to me twice last time, for molesting an 8-year-girl.
I'm going to the juvie right?
- I'm dying... - What?
- ALS. Lou Gehrig's disease.
I'm not your associate,
I'm a partner and what I'm saying is,
it's really, really not so great about being told what to do anymore.
Are you telling me that you are trying to round up enough votes to fire my son?
That's uh executive commit meeting.
Are they gonna fire me?
They are talking about it.
资历
Seniority.
可靠性
Reliability.
责任感
Liability.
说重点  杰克
Get to it, Jake.
资历上  我们在这工作的时间都比尼克长
Seniority: We've all been here Ionger than Nick.
但是他的名字写在门上  而我们的没有
His name's on the door ours are not.
从可靠性来说  尼克有毒瘾  并且在恢复期
Reliability: Nick's addiction and recovery.
- 我儿子的问题  - 是我们的问题
- My son's problems-- - Are our problems.
这就引出了责任感的问题
Which leads me to liability.
伯顿  尼克搞砸了案子
Burton, Nick has botched deals.
他隐瞒了利益冲突问题  现在又让我们被告上了法庭
He's hidden conflicts of interest and now he's gotten us sued.
伯顿  我们很尊重你
As much as we respect you, Burton,
我们也知道你打算要退休了
we know that you're planning to retire in the near future,
而我们需要有一人来接手公司
and we need someone else's name on the door.
呃  他们  想取消你的合伙人资治
Well, they, uh, want to revoke your partnership.
- 他们想让我离开公司吗  - 是的
- They want me out of the firm? - Yeah.
他们选票够吗
Do they have the votes?
斯特拉卡占了九个人中的四票
Straka has four of the nine locked up.
很接近了
lt's gonna be close.
我们只有  呃  你和我两票
We have, well, you and me
那么我们要去说服其他三个人
and then we're just gonna have to sway the other three.
- 什么时候投票  - 星期四  四点
- When's the vote? - Thursday, 4:00.
我来跟杜赛特谈  她一直想要继续做青石塑料  然后
l'll talk to Doucette. She always wanted in on Bluestone Plastics and--
好的  我想我能说服比尔·戈登
Yeah, l think l can sway Bill·Gordon.
我们应该最后找巴里·兰茨堡  他应该是最容易动摇的
We should save Barry·Landsburg for last. He should be the easiest.
他有不少反对斯特拉卡的理由
He's got a few reasons for opposing Straka.
他也有不少反对我的理由
He's got a few reasons to oppose me, too.
儿子  呃
Son, um...
我希望你能留在这
l want you here.
这是我坚持这么久的主要原因
That's the main reason l've stuck around for so damn long.
第三季  第二十一集
法外真情
翻译  大淘子
校对  油 球
特效  转轮 枪
嘿  尼克  请进
Hey, Nick. Come on in.
你希望我接替你工作六周吗
You want me to cover for you for six weeks?
是啊  你知道的  我要开始休产假了
Yeah, you know, just for my maternity leave.
- 预产期是什么时候  - 六月中旬
- When are you due? - Mid June.
你知道的  阿尔文  如果你觉得做不了的话
You know, Alvin, if you don't think that you're up to it
那我就去找别人来给我替班
then l can find someone else to cover for me.
你知道的  阿尔文  如果你觉得做不了的话
You know, Alvin, if you don't think that you're up to it
那我就去找别人来给我替班
then l can find someone else to cover for me.
谁呢
Who?
呃  我也不知道  但是
Well, l don't know, but--
我可以的  露露  真的
l'm up to it, Lulu, really.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
- 嘿  尼克  - 阿尔文
- Hey, Nick. - Alvin.
露露  能跟你说两句吗
Lulu, do you have a second?
可以啊
Yeah.
- 我刚刚见我的缓刑监察员  - 是嘛
- l just saw my probation omicer. - Okay.
我还剩17个小时了
l have 17 hours left.
- 什么意思  - 我的社区服务
- What do you mean? - My community service.
再有17小时  我就做完了
17 hours and l'm done.
嗯  很好啊
Hmm. Okay.
好吧  呃
Well, um...
你知道的  你说有没做完的案子都要转交给其他律师的
You know, all of your open cases will have to be transferred to other attorneys.
当然
Sure.
那我给你的缓刑监察官准备文书
And l'll start the paperwork for your probation officer.
好的
Great. Ok.
你听说没有  这个  凯文  凯文·布朗
You know what? Here. Kevin. Kevin·Brown.
他被指控在学术比赛中强奸一名少女
He's charged with raping a girl in an academic games tournament.
他一直在等待审判
He's been waiting a hell of long time for his trial.
好吧  欢迎来到刑事法庭
Well, welcome to the criminal courts.
有什么问题吗
What's the problem?
那个女孩怀孕了  并且两周之前生下了孩子
The girl was impregnated, and she had the baby two weeks ago.
想把她送给别人领养
Wants to give her up for adoption.
好吧
Okay.
问题是凯文不想放弃他作为父亲的权利  所以
The problem is that Kevin doesn't want to relinquish his parental rights, so...
好的  这个只会花八个小时  那你有其他的
Right. Well, this'll only take eight hours, so do you have another?
哦  当然
Oh, yeah.
好的
Yeah.
给  拿着这个吧
Here, take that.
谢谢
Thank you.
看到这个没有
See this?
塔利克·艾伦解雇了他的律师
Taliek·Allen fired his lawyer.
他上诉失败了  他们会处死他
He loses the appeal, they're gonna execute him.
有什么我能帮忙的吗
Can l help you?
我来见凯文·布朗
l'm here to see Kevin·Brown.
- 我没有强奸她  - 我不是公共辩护人  凯文
- l didn't rape her. - l'm not a public defender, Kevin.
听着  我这三年都没有犯罪
Yo, l haven't committed a crime in three years.
我参加了补习班  在学校的成绩都是A和B
l joined the leg-up program and was gettin' all A's and B's in school.
凯文  凯文
Kevin. Kevin.
你知道法庭正在考虑的是
Do you understand that the court is considering
终止你作为父母的权利吗
terminating your parental rights?
他们不能这样做
They can't do that.
好吧  如果你最后坐牢了  他们就有权利这样
Well, they can if you end up in prison,
或者如果法官相信孩子妈妈的话
or if the judge believes the mother of your baby.
我想说  这都是些废话
l mean, that's some crap right there.
不是废话  你有两次前科
lt's not crap. You have two prior convictions.
一次是吸毒  另一次是袭击他人
One for drugs and another for assault.
但是我没有强奸她
But l didn't rape her.
孩子的妈妈已经同意领养
And the mother's agreed to the adoption.
而且备选家庭都是不错的
And the potential family's an excellent placement.
- 我没有强奸她  - 我知道  我知道
- l didn't rape her. - l get it. l get it.
她之前是我的女朋友
She was my girlfriend.
她之前是的
She was.
她也是很喜欢我的
Like, she was real interested in me
因为我改变了我的生活和所有的一切
for the way l changed my life around and whatever.
之后当他们发现我们在一起时  她就开始反抗我
Then when they caught us together, she turned on me.
我来看看在案子结束之前我能不能留下来
l'll see if l can get a stay until the criminal case is resolved.
而且我甚至一眼都没有看到我的孩子
And l haven't even met my baby.
他们甚至不让我看看她
They won't even let me see her.
塔利克
Taliek.
阿尔文·马斯特森
Alvin·Masterson.
我来这是因为我知道你解雇了你最好的律师
l'm here because l understand you fired your Iatest attorney.
所以  克里斯  你的档案写着你一直呆在自己的牢房里
So, Chris, your file says you wouldn't come out of your cell?
而且你在一周里什么都不吃  并且两个月没有洗澡
Says you didn't eat in over a week and you didn't shower in two months.
我不能去浴室
l can't go into the bathroom.
我甚至不能去普通房间
l can't even go into the common room.
- 为什么  - 因为团伙
- Why not? - Gangs.
- 恩  - 黑人小孩揍了我
- Right. - The black kids beat me up.
而且如果你不加入到白人孩子的阵营  他们基本会把你当黑人孩子对待
And if you don't join the white kids, they basically treat you like a black kid.
好吧  这里的精神病医生  克里斯  他们并没有把你归类成精神病
Well, the psychiatrists here, Chris, are not classifying you as mentally ill.
所以你不能一直呆在这
So you can't stay here any longer.
但是我也不用回到曼科了  是吧
But l don't have to go back to Manko, right?
这得由法官来定
That'll be up to the judge.
也许你可以把我送去寄养家庭什么的
Well, maybe you could put me in a foster family or something?
这得由法官来定
That'll be up to the judge.
也许你可以把我送去寄养家庭什么的
Well, maybe you could put me in a foster family or something?
好吧  我试试看可不可以
Well, l'll see what l can do.
法林先生  我真的不能再回曼科了
l can't go back to Manko, Mr. Fallin.
法官大人  终止我委托人父母权利的动议
Your Honor, the motion to terminate my client's parental rights
还是为时过早的
is completely premature.
法官大人  他的当事人因强奸罪被捕
His client was arrested for rape, Your Honor.
凯文·布朗还没有被定罪
Kevin·Brown has not been convicted of any crime.
只有一项指控
There's only been an accusation.
这是一个相当严重的指控
Quite a serious accusation.
但也只是一项指控
But it's only an accusation.
而也这也不是你当事人第一次
And it's not the first time your client--
如果他在刑事审判中被判无罪
lf he's found not guilty in his criminal trial,
那么他就应该有跟孩子保持关系的机会
then he should be given the opportunity to have a relationship with his child.
刑事定罪并不是必须的
A criminal conviction is not necessary
因为法院有权终止凯文·布朗的权利
for this court to terminate Kevin·Brown's rights.
法官大人  富勒夫妇是一个模范家庭
Your Honor, the Fullers have identified an exemplary family
现在也准备好领养
who are ready to adopt now.
没有人的孩子是应该被带走的
No one should have their child taken away from them
仅仅因为他们被指控犯罪
simply because they've been accused of a crime.
你知道找一个家庭有多困难吗
Do you understand how dimicult it is to find families
能愿意收养强奸怀孕后出生的孩子
to adopt children conceived in rape?
我会保留裁决  一两天后给出最后决定
l'll reserve judgment. You'll get my decision in a day or two.
曼科中心的环境太差了  导致我的当事人
The conditions at the Manko Center are so bad that my client
精神崩溃  并且被送到了精神病医院
had a mental breakdown and was institutionalized.
但没有发现患上精神疾病
And found not to be mentally ill.
他不从自己的牢房出来  不吃  也不洗澡
He doesn't come out of his cell. He doesn't eat. He doesn't shower.
据医生所说  这些行为是他自己想做的  而不是由于疾
According to the doctors, those behaviors are his choice, not an illness.
好吧  曼科中心应该是一个拘留所  而不是监狱
Well, the Manko Center is supposed to be are formatory, not a prison.
因为拉普先生袭击一名八岁的女孩  我判他去训练营
l sentenced Mr. Rapp to boot camp for assaulting an eight-year-old girl.
之后他袭击了一名社会工作者
He then attacked a social worker
一个尝试帮他从那转出来的人
who was trying to help get him transferred from that very camp.
法官大人  但是事实是
But the fact remains, Your Honor
曼科中心并没有是我的当事人恢复正常生活
that the Manko Center is not rehabilitating my client.
法林先生  事实是
The fact remains, Mr. Fallin,
曼科中心是给最糟糕的情况预留的
that the Manko Center is reserved for the worst of the worst.
如果让我说  他就只配待在那里
lf you ask me, he's more than earned his place there.
- 哦  嘿  很抱歉我迟到了  - 没事
- Oh, hey. Sorry l'm late. - That's all right.
呃  我能喝杯伏特加吗  你要来杯可乐还是别的什么
Uh, can l have a vodka-tonic? You want a Coke or something?
不  我不要了
No, l'm fine.
所以  有什么事吗
So, what's up?
坐下吃点吗
You want to sit down?
不用了  我吃过了
No, l already ate.
谢谢
Thanks.
我们坐下聊  好吗
Let's sit down, okay?
好吧
Okay.
我从没想过你会想把我赶出公司
l had no idea you wanted me out of the firm.
是啊
Yeah.
好吧  我只是在做我认为能让公司未来更好的事
Well, l'm just doing what l feel is best for the future of the firm.
是吗
Really?
而且如果有人问我  我会告诉他们你是一个一流的律师
And if anyone asks me, l will tell them that you are a top-notch lawyer,
告诉他们你能带来客户  告诉他们你很有才华
that you bring in clients and that you are talented.
但是现在你应该离开
But it's time for you to move on.
从我自己的公司离开吗
From my own firm?
好吧   看到没有  这就是问题的所在
Well, see that's where the problem rests,
因为我和希金斯，马斯顿和斯通
because me and Higgins and Marston and Stone
来的时间都比你长
have all been there Ionger than you have.
我们付出的比你多  我们也有比你更多的客户
We bill more than you do. We have more clients than you.
坦白说  我们很不喜欢你的名字出现在门上
And frankly, we're tired of having your name on the door.
我的意思是说  在我们看来  法林&法林
l mean, the way we see it, Fallin & Fallin
其实应是法林&希金斯&马斯特森&斯通
is really Fallin & Higgins & Marston & Stone...
&斯特拉卡
& Straka...
&法林
& Fallin.
但是你插队了
But you jumped the line.
我知道  你不可能将这件事情私人化
Look, l know there's no way that you can't take this personally,
但是你不应该
but you shouldn't.
我挺喜欢你的  尼克  是真的挺喜欢
l like you Nick. l really do.
我很抱歉事情发展到这一步
l'm sorry it had to come to this.
是啊
Yeah.
- 嘿  - 嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
所以  杰克那边怎么样了
So how'd it go with Jake?
我不认为周四那群家伙有谁会改变阵营
l don't think any of those guys are gonna change their position by Thursday.
好吧  多赛特现在支持我们了
Well, Doucette's with us.
很好  那你答应给她什么了
Great. What'd you have to give her?
- 青石  - 多少
- Bluestone. - How much?
全部
All of it.
好吧  明天我要和比尔·戈登开个早餐会
Well, tomorrow l have a breakfast meeting with Bill·Gordon.
嗯
Hmm.
好吧  我明天晚餐的时候和兰德斯堡约一下
Well, l'll set up, uh, some kinda dinner thing with Landsburg tomorrow night.
好的
Right.
哦  周四我也会做完所有社区服务
Oh, l'll be finishing my community service on Thursday.
能做完吗
Are you?
缓刑基本结束了
Probation's almost over.
好吧  XX
Well, you're working full-time.
斯特拉卡没法跟你比
Straka can't compete with that.
他不能
He can't.
法官不打算给我机会了  是吗
This judge isn't gonna give me a chance, is she?
是的  我想她不会给了
No, l don't think she will.
如果她把孩子带走  我就不可能再看见她了  是吗
lf she takes the baby away, l won't have any way to see her again, right?
是的
Right.
能让我看看孩子吗  五分钟就行
Think l could get five minutes with the baby?
也许吧  如果在法官裁决之前你主动同意终止你的权利
Maybe. If you agree to relinquish your rights before the judge rules,
我也许能做一些什么
l may be able to work something out.
我从没有见到过她  法林先生  我就是想看看她
l've never seen her, Mr. Fallin. l just want to see her once.
拜托你了  我很抱歉  我真的不能待在这
Please. l'm sorry. l just can't stay here.
- 怎么了  - 他不出来上课
- What's going on? - He won't come out for class.
让我跟他谈谈吧  我是他的律师
Let me talk to him. l'm his lawyer.
法林先生
Mr. Fallin?
如果我同意你跟他说几句话  你愿意出来吗
lf l let you talk to this guy, you'll come out?
三分钟
Three minutes.
- 我昨晚听到他们说话了  - 谁
- l heard them last night. - Who?
那些黑人孩子
The black kids.
我听到他们中有一个人说他要揍我
l heard one of them say he was gonna stick me.
- 谁  - 我没有看到他的脸
- Who? - l didn't see his face.
- 他们在哪  - 我不知道  是在熄灯之后
- Where were they? - l don't know. It was after lights out.
- 我听到了  先生  - 好的
- l heard 'em, man. - Right.
你知道他们会做什么吗
You know what they do?
他们会戳你的腋窝  这样你的肺就会被刺穿
They stab you in the armpit so your lung gets punctured.
克里斯  这里有安保的  这些人会保护你的
Chris, there's security here. There's people here to protect you.
你不知道你在说什么
You don't know what you're talking about.
你还有三个月了  当你满18周岁了  你就能从这出去
You got three months to go. When you're 18, you're out of here.
就按照规矩  去学校  老实一点
Just play by the rules. Go to school and keep your head down.
你真的认为这样就可以了吗
You really think that'll work?
不要太张扬  好吗
Just keep to yourself, okay?
这是你需要的修订本
Here's the revised copies you requested.
是的  好的  谢谢
Yeah, okay. Thank you.
- 嘿  尼克  - 嘿
- Hey, Nick. - Hey.
现在比尔·戈登也在我们这边了
So Bill·Gordon's in.
需要给他豪斯特勒煤炭公司的一半  但是他还是加入我们的阵营了
Had to give him half of Hostetler Coal, but he's in.
你跟兰德博格聊过了吗
Did you talk to Landsburg already?
我不认为他已经做好决定了
l don't think he's made his mind up yet.
什么情况
What is it?
斯特拉卡他昨晚订婚了
Straka. He got engaged last night.
- 跟凯特·肖吗  - 是的
- To Kate Shaw? - Yeah.
这是一步好棋  老人有很多钱  也有很好的关系
That's a good move. Old man's got a lot of money, good connections.
真是一步好棋
lt's a good move.
我最好去说一句祝贺
l'd better go say congratulations.
詹姆斯强烈反对死刑
James was against the death penalty, vehemently.
我知道他会反对塔利克·艾伦的判刑
And l know he would be opposed to what is about to happen to Taliek·Allen.
我正在处理塔利克的上诉
l am handling Taliek's appeal.
如果你们能给我一份宣誓书  那就帮了大忙了
lt would help me a great deal if l could get an affidavit from you all,
声明你们知道詹姆斯对死刑的看法
stating that you knew James' view on capital punishment
而且你们支持判塔利克无期徒刑  而不是死刑
and that you support a life sentence for Taliek instead of death.
我知道这是一个艰难的时刻
l know this is a difficult time.
并不会
No.
当我看到他们把我弟弟詹姆斯按倒在地上的时候
When l watched them lower my brother James into the ground,
那才是艰难的时刻
that was a difficult time.
今天  知道塔利克·艾伦会像狗一样被杀掉
Today, knowing that Taliek·Allen will be put down like the dog he is,
这是一段轻松的时刻  马斯特森先生
that's a very easy time, Mr. Masterson.
詹姆斯不会希望这样的
James wouldn't want it that way.
我弟弟还希望能活着呢
My brother would've wanted to be alive.
除非你想道歉  否则不要再给我们打电话了
Don't call on us again unless you plan to apologize.
安琪拉
Angela.
怎么样了
What's going on?
- 我请见詹姆斯的家人来见了一面  - 为什么啊
- l asked James' family to meet with me. - What for?
为了签署宣誓书
To sign an affidavit.
我代表塔利克·艾伦上诉
l'm representing Taliek·Allen in his appeal.
- 什么时候  - 昨天
- Since when? - Yesterday.
为什么
Why?
你不反对死刑吗
You're not opposed to the death penalty?
我反对啊  我对这个也有意见
l'm opposed. l have my issues with it.
那么  你要不要考虑签署一下宣誓书
Well, would you consider signing an amidavit
说你知道詹姆斯也是反对的
stating that you knew James was against it?
你希望我签署
You want me to sign something stating
我知道詹姆斯反对死刑的宣誓书吗
that l knew James was against the death penalty?
- 是的  - 他真的反对吗
- Yes. - Was he?
当然反对的
Well, yeah.
并不知道
Didn't know that.
嗨
Hi.
嗨  瓦奥莱特
Hi, Violet.
你什么时候到的
When did you get here?
我也不知道
l don't know.
你在这等一下  好吗
You wait right here, okay?
阿尔文  我需要你接手我的一个客户
Alvin, l need you to take over one of my clients.
不好意思  我现在很忙
No, l'm very busy.
她的名字叫瓦奥莱特·桑兹  她的养父母将搬到内华达州
Her name is Violet·Sands. Her foster parents are moving to Nevada.
她需要一个好的寄宿家庭
She needs a good placement.
你怎么不能管她
Why can't you take her?
我要在周末之前做完
l'm gonna be done by the end of the week.
- 做完什么  - 做完这个
- Done with what? - Done with this.
- 做完这吗  - 我还剩11小时
- Done here? - l got 1 1 hours to go.
瓦奥莱特  这是阿尔文·马斯特森
Violet, this is Alvin·Masterson.
从现在开始  由阿尔文来照顾你
Alvin will be taking care of you from now on.
- 嘿  - 嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
- 你听说杰克和凯特的事了吗  - 是的
- Did you hear about Jake and Kate? - Yeah.
我都不知道我该怎么做了
l don't know what l'm gonna do about that.
我的意思是  她是我的好朋友之一
l mean, she's one of my really good friends.
你认为她不了解杰克吗
You don't think she knows about Jake?
好吧  她同意嫁给他  所以  不  我觉得她不知道
Well, she agreed to marry him. So no, l don't think she knows.
我应该告诉她  你不觉得吗
l have to tell her, don't you think?
你打算跟她说什么
What are you gonna say?
呃  我不知道  可能说他以前跟男人睡过
Um, l don't know. That he's been with men, l guess?
随便你吧
lt's up to you.
我并不关系你的尼克都做了什么
l don't care what you say Nick did!
你把尼克投出去了  你也把我投出去了
You vote Nick out, you vote me out as well.
明白了吗
ls that understood?
听说你要结婚了
l heard you're getting married.
是啊
That's right.
恭喜  凯特很不错
Congratulations. Kate's very nice.
是啊
Yeah.
你真的有很多转变
That's a lot of changes happening for you.
新的未婚妻  新的客户  新的衣服
New fiancée. New clients. New clothes.
好吧  你知道  我觉得我们也许应该一起坐下来
Well, you know, l was thinking maybe we could sit down together
然后敲定一下新的薪酬结构
and hammer out a new pay structure,
基于计费工时  和源信贷合作
based on billable hours, working with source credit.
搞清楚谁能从每个客户那里得到什么  而不是把整个公司搞得四分五裂
Figure out who gets what of each client instead of tearing this entire firm apart.
你在威胁我吗
Are you threatening me?
为什么要这么说
Why would you say that?
你问什么要提到凯特
Why would you bring up Kate?
杰克  我是在祝贺你们的好消息
Jake, l was congratulating you
on your good news.
所以  我们可以找一份客户名单  单独坐下来
So, we can get a client list, we can sit down together, alone,
然后试着安排好一切
and try to come to some kind of an arrangement.
是啊  但是你为什么要把凯特卷进来
Yeah, but why would you bring Kate into this?
我没有  杰克
l'm not, Jake.
如果我想跟凯特说你的事情  我早就说了
lf l wanted to tell Kate about you, l would've done it already.
你就是在威胁我
You're threatening me.
我一直信守对你的承诺  没告诉别人
l've kept my promises to you. l've covered for you.
从没有说过关于你的情况
l've kept quiet about your situation.
所以  我想我现在有点好奇  你为什么现在要这样想我
So l guess l'm a little curious as to why you would be doing this to me now.
你是在威胁我
You're threatening me.
我妈妈明天晚上想邀请你的妈妈来吃饭
My mom wants to invite your mom over for dinner tomorrow night.
好啊
Good.
哦  我妈妈已经雇了一个非常棒的婚礼策划师
Oh, my mother has hired this insane wedding planner.
我爸爸说他要在威廉佩·恩酒店订三层楼
And my dad thought he might reserve three floors at the William·Penn
婚礼的周末
the weekend of the wedding.
凯特  你还记不记得  呃
Kate, do you remember, um...
你还记得我被抢劫的时候吗
Do you remember when l was mugged?
记得
Yeah.
好吧  其实不只是  那样
Well, it wasn't just... that.
我 被  呃
l was, uh...
我被性侵了
l was attacked... sexually.
那个男人  他  呃
The man, he, uh...
好吧  他袭击了我
Well, he attacked me.
你之前为什么不告诉我
Why didn't you tell me?
我  我觉得很丢人
l--l was ashamed.
我  呃
l, uh...
我猜你可能会觉得我太弱了
l guess l thought you might think that l was weak.
他强奸了你吗
He raped you?
现在有些人  呃
And now some people are, uh...
其实  他们  他们在  呃
well, they're--they're, um...
散布谣言  说我
spreading rumors that l'm...
你想跟我说什么
What are you trying to tell me?
我只是希望这一切都能过去
l just want to get past it.
我想说的是  我想我能理解
What l'm saying is l guess l understand
如果因为这个让你不想跟我在一起
if this makes you not want to be with me.
杰克  我爱你
Jake, l love you.
我应该更早告诉你的
l should've told you sooner.
听着  如果你需要一些时间来考虑这件事  我能理解的
Look, l just understand if you need some time to think about this now.
有效的法律顾问协助  这才是我们的论点
lneffective assistance of counsel. That's our argument.
看到这里没有
See here?
还有
And...
这里
here.
你证明了你对詹姆斯有很强烈的愤怒
You testified about the intense rage you felt towards James
因为他的攻击造成了你的毁容
because his attack caused your disfigurement,
因为你失去了自己的孩子
because you lost your child.
所以呢
So?
好吧  你的律师从来不为极端的情绪做辩护
Well, your lawyer never argued extreme emotional disturbance.
所以你可能不会得到正面的直接辩护
Affirmative defenses that probably couldn't have gotten you off,
但他本可以将刑期减为无期徒刑  而不是  呃
but could have mitigated the sentence to life instead of, uh...
好吧  而不是其他刑罚
well, instead of the alternative.
他想要跟孩子相处多长时间
How long does he want to spend with the baby?
几分钟  就是亲自看看她
A few minutes. Just to see her in person.
如果你们同意  凯文会选择终止他作为父母的权利
lf you agree, Kevin will relinquish his parental rights.
好吧  我觉得没什么不好的
Well, l don't see why not.
所以是可以的吗
So it's agreed?
当然
Sure.
我得先说明  我需要先跟我妻子说说  但是我并不觉得有什么不好的
l mean, l have to talk to my wife first, but l don't think there'll be a problem.
好的
Great.
我先去请求法官的许可  之后我们再安排见面
l'll request permission from the judge, and we'll set up the meeting.
- 好的  - 你确定你希望这样吗
- Okay. - You sure you're all right with this?
是的  我就是想看看她  法林先生
Yeah, l just want to see her, Mr. Fallin.
- 我能问你点事情吗  - 什么
- May l ask you something? - What?
- 在这待着有多糟糕  - 你想说什么
- How bad is it in here? - What do you mean?
我是你们这一个孩子的律师
l represent this kid in your unit.
他害怕到从来不从牢房出来
He so frightened he never comes out of his cell.
- 什么  那个白胖子吗  - 是的
- What, that fat white kid? - Right.
他自作自受  他太紧张了  总是逼着自己那样想
He got it bad. He's too nervous. Calls attention to himself.
但是他说要想在这里生存下去  就得加入一边
But he says to survive in this place you gotta join a gang.
有些孩子是这样的
Some kids do.
而且一直跟我说如果他加入了  就会有大麻烦
Keeps telling me if he joins, there's gonna be trouble.
- 血进血出  - 血进吗
- Blood in, blood out. - Blood in?
是啊  你必须要通过XX来抢一个自己的位置
Yeah, you gotta earn your place by jumpin' somebody, drawing blood.
- 我们之后再联系  - 好的
- l'll be in touch. - All right.
嘿
Hey!
我一直低头做人  法林先生
l kept my head down, Mr. Fallin.
就像你说的一样
Just like you said.
我一直很低调
l kept my head down.
格拉斯先生格拉斯太太  我需要知道
l need to know the minute Mr. and Mrs. Glass
尽快定下来  好吗
come to a decision, all right?
谢谢
Thank you.
- 嘿  尼克  - 嘿  最近怎么样
- Hey, Nick. - Hey, how are you?
这几天太忙了
lt's been a wild couple a days.
我想也是  恭喜
l bet. Well, congratulations.
谢谢
Thanks.
我刚刚看到凯特了
l just saw Kate.
哦  是的  她  呃
Oh, yeah. She, uh...
她过来  想要聊聊杰克的事情
She came by and she wanted to talk about Jake.
我猜他可能跟她说了那次袭击的事  她有点吓坏了
l guess he told her about the attack. She was kinda freaked out about it.
你说什么了吗
Did you say something?
没有  我也不能  我只是
No. l couldn't. l just...
我转了话题  跟她聊了聊婚礼派对的事
l just changed the subject and talked about her wedding shower.
- 你还好吗  - 还好
- You okay? - Yeah.
凯特跟我说你和杰克在工作中有些问题
Kate told me that you and Jake were having some problems at work.
是的
Yeah.
那么  现在怎么样了
Well, what's going on?
杰克想把我从我的公司中赶出去
Jake's trying to get me thrown out of my firm.
什么  你怎么没有跟我说
What? Why didn't you tell me?
哦  你不需要有压力的  你马上就要生了
Oh, you don't need the stress. You're about to have a baby.
好吧  我希望你不要觉得尴尬
Well, l hope you're not embarrassed about it.
不会  一点也不会
No, not at all.
因为我并不在意你是否在那家公司工作
Because l don't care if you work for that firm or not.
好吧  我还是很在意的
Well, l kinda do.
- 嘿  - 嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
你还有几个小时了
How many hours do you have left?
四个
Four.
- 马上就结束了  - 是啊
- End of an era. - Right.
终于要结束了
End of an era.
这支笔
This pen...
怎么了
Yes?
这支笔是我爸爸高中毕业的时候收到的
This pen was given to my father for his high school graduation
我爷爷给的
by my grandfather.
是1954年的XX  金尖
lt's a 1954 Alt-Rodere, gold-tip.
花了我爷爷一周的薪水
lt cost my grandfather a week's salary.
现在我想把它给你  尼克
l want you to have it, Nick.
阿尔文  你什么都不用给我的
Alvin, you don't have to give me anything.
为了让你记得在这的时光
To remember your time here.
谢谢
Thank you.
你得承认  你是挺喜欢在这工作的
You gotta admit, you kinda liked working here.
没有  呃  我可没有
Nope. No. l, uh... l didn't.
谢谢  非常犯些
Thank you. Thank you.
尼克  这是达姆森法官办公室给你的
Nick, this just came from Judge Damsen's office.
好的  谢谢
Great. Thank you.
- 我知道  - 你这道这意味着什么吗
- l knew it. - You understand what that means?
根据法官所说的  我再也不是我孩子的爸爸了
That l'm not my baby's daddy anymore,
according to this judge.
格拉斯夫妇改变了对于你看孩子的想法
The Glasses have changed their mind about your visit.
什么意思
What?
格拉斯太太有点担心
Mrs. Glass is concerned.
担心什么  她害怕我吗
Concerned? What, she scared of me?
她相信了你的事情
She believes the story.
我从来没有  先生  我真的没有强奸那个女生
l have never-- Man, l did not rape that girl!
但是  她相信了那个女孩的事
Well, she believes the girl's story.
- 但是他已经答应我了  先生  - 很抱歉
- But he promised me, man! - l'm sorry.
不  不行  你听到了的  他已经答应我了
No, man! He promised me! You heard him promise me, man!
克里斯  你感觉怎么样
Chris, how are you feeling?
真的是谢谢你了  混蛋  他们快杀了我了
Thanks a lot, jerk-om. They're gonna kill me now.
你在说什么啊
What are you talking about?
你跟卡拉克森主管说了我的事情吗
You told Director Clarkson what happened to me?
是啊  我当然说了
Yeah, of course l did.
他去找那个打我的家伙了
He went after the kid that did this to me,
现在他的同伙要杀了吧  除非我做些什么
and now his buddies are gonna kill me... unless l can do something.
你应该把我弄出去
You should have got me out of here.
而不是把时间都花在那个黑小子身上
lnstead of spending all your time with that black kid,
你应该来帮我的
you should have been helping me instead.
第六修正案保证了所有人
The Sixth Amendment guarantees all persons
在辩护时能得到律师的协助
assistance of counsel for their defense.
法院也一再解释这是适当的
lt has been repeatedly interpreted by the courts to mean adequate
并且熟练的法律顾问
and skilled counsel.
正如我在法庭上努力阐明的
As l have made it painfully clear to this court,
塔利克·艾路从来没有这样的代表
Taliek·Allen was never amorded such representation.
英联邦想要剥夺塔利克·艾伦的生命
The Commonwealth wants to take Taliek·Allen's life.
他被判处死刑
He has been condemned to die
尽管我们宪法的规定
despite the fact that the rules of our Constitution
没有被遵守
have not been adhered to,
这很明显是不公平的
and that is an irreversible injustice.
死亡不是随便就能发给谁的东西
Death is not something to be handed out arbitrarily.
法官大人  我们之前已经达成一致
An agreement was reached, Your Honor.
这不在我们的考虑范围内
For which there was no consideration.
我的当事人愿意签署终止协议
My client was willing to sign the termination papers.
这样还不够吗
ls that not enough?
这项协议是建立在假设的基础上的
The agreement was based on the presumption
他的签名才是必须的
his signature would be necessary.
到此为止  协议不能强制执行
lt isn't any longer. The agreement isn't enforceable.
格拉斯先生  请听我说完  我需要再跟你谈谈
Mr. Glass, if you'd just hear me out. l need to talk to you about...
尼克  你的父亲在最高法院辩护过对吧
Nick, your father's argued before the Supreme Court, right?
- 是的  - 你那个时候帮他处理案子了吗
- Yeah. - Did you help him with that?
参与了一点吧  怎么了
A little. Why?
我起草了调卷领  也许你可以看看
l drafted a Writ of Certiorari. Maybe you could take a look at it?
你要上诉到最高法院吗
You're gonna appeal to the Supreme Court?
我不能就这样看着他死  尼克
l can't just let him die, Nick.
嗨
Hi.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
躲起来
Hiding.
在躲谁
From who?
他
Him.
为什么啊
Why?
我不喜欢他
l don't like him.
好吧  露露
Well-- Lulu!
来一下
Come here.
这是露露  先让她照顾你一会  好吗
This is Lulu. She's gonna take care of you just for a minute, okay?
就一会
Just a minute.
法律顾问的协助吗
lnemective assistance of counsel?
值得一试
lt's worth a shot.
- 到底怎么回事  - 什么意思
- What's this about? - What do you mean?
我想知道到底怎么回事
No, what is this really about?
死刑是野蛮的
The death penalty's barbaric.
阿尔文  我并不认为只是关于死刑的问题
l don't think it's about the death penalty, Alvin.
什么意思  你觉得是跟我自己有关吗  不是的
What, you think this is about me? It's not.
事实上是塔利克·艾伦不应该死
lt's about the fact that Taliek·Allen does not deserve to die.
每个人都有活着的权利
Everyone has a right to life.
是的
Right.
好吧  真的不是我自己的原因
Well, it's not about me.
很抱歉给你打了好多次电话
l'm sorry l called you so many times.
- 没关系的  - 我不确定我还能跟谁说
- It's all right. - l wasn't sure who else to call.
关于这件事  露露有点奇怪  所以我猜想我们可以聊聊
Lulu was being weird about it, and l guess l thought we could talk.
好吧
Okay.
我知道你和杰克现在有些矛盾
l know that you and Jake are having some problems,
但是我觉得你是最了解他的人
but l thought, well, you're the person who knows him the best.
好吧  可能我不应该这样说
Well, l wouldn't say that.
但是杰克之前一直在夸你
Jake always spoke so highly of you.
哦  很高兴听到这个
Well, that's nice to hear.
但是  现在变了
Now that's... changed.
杰克变了很多
Jake's kind of changed.
他跟我说了那次袭击
He told me about the attack,
之后我就在想  怎么会发生这样的事情
and l guess l started to think about how something like that might happen,
一个人如何发现自己处于那样的环境中
how someone might find themselves in that type of a situation.
然后我就在想那次袭击是不是真的
And l guess l began to wonder if the attack was random
或者是由于他生活方式造成的结果
or if it was the result of a lifestyle.
好吧
Okay.
所以我在想  也许你能跟我说说这件事
And l guess l thought that maybe you could tell me something about that.
我很抱歉  塔利克  这是法庭第三次驳回我们的上诉了
l'm really sorry, Taliek, but the Third Circuit denied our appeal.
但是你一定不要放弃
But you can't give up hope.
我已经向最高法院递交了一些材料
l've filed some papers with the Supreme Court.
希望他们能同意审理我们的案子
Hopefully they'll agree to hear our case.
你知道他们是怎么做的吗
Do you know how they do it?
什么
What?
他们怎么杀死我
How they kill me?
靠注射
lt's an injection.
当毒瘾犯了的时候  他们会给我换上尿布
They put me in a diaper because sometimes when the drugs hit you,
因为你会失去对全身功能的控制
you lose control of your functions.
塔利克
Taliek.
然后他们会把我绑起来
Then they strap me down.
他们给我三针
They give me three shots.
第一针应该是让我睡着
First one's supposed to make me sleep.
第二针应该是不让我呼吸
The second one's supposed to stop me from breathing.
最后一个应该是让我的心脏停工
And the last one's supposed to shut down my heart,
让它停止跳动
stop it from pumping.
我听说有的时候第一针甚至不会起效果
l heard sometimes the first shot doesn't even work.
所以你就躺在那
So you lie there.
就只能躺在那
You just lie there and...
你想想要呼吸
You want to breathe...
但是你动不了
but you can't move...
之后你能感觉到你的心脏停止
and you can feel your heart stopping.
你能感觉到的
You can feel it, man.
他们说这是世界上最痛苦的了
They say it's the worst pain in the world.
对于看着的人来说  你就只是躺在那里
To everybody watching, it looks like you're just lying there.
但是你能感觉到
But you can feel it.
你能感觉到自己慢慢死亡
You can feel yourself dying.
你叫我来吗
You wanted to see me?
是啊  进来吧
Yeah, come on in.
听着  你会LSP吗
Listen, are you through with that LSP?
一点点吧
Just about.
那你会某种形式或者东西
Are you gonna have some kind of a form or something
能实时向别人展示会议吗
to show these guys in time for the meeting?
是的  我会
Yeah, l will.
好吧  我们有四票  他们也有四票
Well, we got four votes. They got four.
我觉得最后就看兰德斯堡了
l think it's gonna come down to Landsburg.
我觉得你需要就在会议室说服他
l guess you're gonna have to convince him right in the room.
好的
Okay.
尼古拉斯  嗯  我认真的  如果他们把你投出去  我就
Nicholas, um, l meant what l said. If they vote you out, l'm--
别  别  不要这样
Please. Please, don't do that.
好吧  儿子  这就是我想的
Well, that's the way l feel, son.
这没有人对你有意见  是我  一直都是因为我
No one here has a problem with you. It's me. It's always been me.
不  我是认真的
No. l meant what l said.
我求你  如果他们把我投出去了  你要留下来
l'm asking you. If they vote me out, then you stay.
会议四点开始
The meeting's at 4.
尼克
Nick.
我就是想跟你说谢谢
l just wanted to say thank you.
我知道昨晚你跟凯特聊过了
l know you talked to Kate last night.
不用谢我
Don't thank me.
- 好吧  我的意思是你本可以  - 我不会的
- Well, l mean you could've-- - l wouldn't.
我知道
l knew that.
她说你变了  我希望是真的
She said you've changed. l hope that's true.
我已经变回来了  凯特什么都不需要担心了
l have changed. Kate's got nothing to worry about.
好吧  说实话  我以前更喜欢你一点
Well, truth be told, l think l liked you a little better before.
尼克  呃  今天我不会改变我的投票
Nick, uh, l'm not changing my vote today.
我知道了
l figured that.
检查了所有当事人信息  我都提交了结案
Gone over all my clients, l filed the closed cases,
没做完的转给了其他律师
transferred the active ones to the other lawyers.
好吧  这个是给你的缓刑官的
Okay. Well, this is for your probation officer.
你还有20分钟
You still have 20 minutes, though.
好吧  在回去的路上我需要去曼科中心  这样时间就够了
Well, l'm stopping off at the Manko Centeron the way back to work.
我得去送点东西
l have to drop something off.
尼克  我开玩笑呢
Nick, l was kidding.
我得签一下这个
l gotta sign this.
好吧  应该就这样了
Well, l guess that's it.
恭喜你  你全做完了
Congratulations. You're done.
谢谢
Thank you.
你认为现在情况有改变了吗
You think things are gonna be different now?
是吧
Yeah.
一切都更好了  露露
Things are gonna be better, Lulu.
这只会让一切变得更好
This is only gonna make things better.
你的会什么时候开始
What time is your meeting?
四点
4.
祝你好运
Good luck.
谢谢
Thank you.
最高法院拒绝了我们的提议
The Supreme Court refused to grant Cert.
他们不会管我们的案子了
They won't hear our case.
所以  我已经联系了赦免委员会准备听证会
So, l've contacted the Board of Pardons for a hearing.
- 你觉得这样会有用吗  - 可能会  会有用的
- You think that'll work? - It might. It could.
我们顺其自然吧
Let's just let it be.
塔利克
Taliek--
听着  我真的是受不了了  解雇律师  再上诉
Look, l can't do this anymore. Firing lawyers, filing appeals.
这所有的事情只不过是在拖延一个我们都知道的结果
Look, all these things just delay what we all know is gonna happen.
别把我晾在这  塔利克
Don't walk out on me, Taliek.
听着  我不能在这种没结果的事上投希望
Look, l can't get my hopes up for nothing.
别让我一个人努力
Don't walk out on me!
在过去的日子里  我没有一天不在想念我的朋友詹姆斯
There isn't a day that goes by that l don't miss my friend James!
他是个好人  塔利克
He was a good man, Taliek.
聪明  又幽默
Smart. Funny.
我没有一天不在你造成的痛苦里挣扎
There's not a day that goes by that l don't struggle with the pain that you caused!
但我想说的是
What l'm saying...
詹姆斯的死并不需要造成比现在更多的痛苦
is James' death doesn't need to cause any more pain than it already has.
所以拜托
So please...
别让我自己一个人努力
don't walk out on me.
谢谢
Thank you.
嘿
Hey.
法林先生
Mr. Fallin.
我给你带了些东西
l brought you something.
他们叫她莉拉
They're calling her Lila.
莉拉
Lila?
你的孩子
That's your baby girl.
莉拉
Lila.
嘿  法林先生  如你所知
Hey, Mr. Fallin, just so you know,
我没有强奸那个女孩
l didn't rape that girl.
你早晚会发现我没有强奸她
And you gonna see that l didn't rape her.
过得怎么样  克里斯
How you doing, Chris?
好点了
Better.
比之前好点了
l'm better now.
- 你好点了吗  - 我好点了
- You doing better? - l'm better.
怎么回事
Why is that?
我感觉好点了  法林先生
l'm better now, Mr. Fallin.
嘿  兄弟们  这是莉拉  是我的女儿
Hey, yo. This is Lila. This is my daughter.
哥们  这是  看
Man, this is-- Look at that!
把照片还给我
Give me my picture back.
你为那个家伙做什么了
What did you do for that guy?
哦  他只是一个当事人
Oh, he's just a client.
把照片还给我
Give me the picture back.
听着  我
Listen, l'm gonna...
我给你写一个电话
l'm gonna write down a number.
如果你以后任何事情  给我打电话
lf you need anything, you call me,
而且我也会保证你能有一个很好的律师的
and l'll make sure you get a very good lawyer.
我不需要你的任何东西  法林先生
l don't need anything from you, Mr. Fallin.
嘿  你确定一下  这真的是凯文的孩子吗
Yo, check it out. This is really Kevin's kid, man.
是  是他的孩子
Yeah, it is.
都跟你说了  这就是我的女儿
l told you! This is my daughter right here!
你该走了
lt's time for you to leave.
你去哪了
Where were you?
很抱歉
l'm sorry.
现在都不重要了
It doesn't matter now.
很抱歉
l'm sorry.
我能问你点事情吗
Can l ask you something?
你做好选择了吗
Did you have a choice?
什么意思  什么选择
What do you mean, did l have a choice?
在这  还是离开
To be here... or not?
你做好选择了吗
Did you have a choice?
没有
No.
是的
Yes.
Xgun擦枪小组 有偿招募译制成员 诚邀阁下
加入Q群：545053435
请注明职务：翻译、听译、aegisub特效（熟练手）
对字幕有任何意见和建议的同学请加Q群：544487177